《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
克里尔神父
Father Creel.
你抓到韦恩家的男孩了吗
You have the Wayne boy?
还没呢
Not yet.
有些实际问题还有待解决
There are some practical matters that have to be resolved first.
企鹅先生
Mr. Penguin?
救救我
Help me.
这是杀死你父母的凶手的名字
This is the name of the man who killed your parents...
你把公司卖给我
Sell me your company,
我就把这个送你做签约礼
I will give you this as a signing gift.
我最近很不乖
I've been a very bad girl.
你是个好女人
You're a good woman.
你只是病了而已
You're just sick.
我就知道你对我还有感觉
I knew you still had feelings for me.
我想给你看点东西
I want to show you something.
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
我能问问罪名是什么吗
May I ask what the charge is?
绑架折磨奥布雷·詹姆斯
The kidnapping and torture of Aubrey James.
不  告诉我是谁杀了他们
No! Tell me who killed them!
居然还这么合身简直难以置信
Can you believe it still fits?
别逼我杀你
Don't make me kill you.
动手吧  吉姆  干掉我
Do it, Jim. Do me.
杀了他
Kill him!
结束了
It's over.
还没呢
Not yet.
撑住
Hold on.
我爱你  亲爱的
I love you, baby.
不要
No!
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 艾瑞卡   大K   木浅   辰星晓Reginamoon   Silence
翻译 盐湖凉开水   DustD   charcie   小胖纸Amy   草草
时间轴 风吹来的那片云
后期 宝宝   校对 草草   总监 草草
盖勒文市长被捕
早啊
Morning.
有事吗
Help you?
有人告诉我来点份皇家海史密斯
I was told to order a Highsmith Royale.
现在喝酒有点早吧
Bit early, don't you think?
我说了要皇家海史密斯
I said Highsmith Royale.
不加冰
No ice.
给你
There you go, man.
有什么能帮你的
How may I help you?
我要杀一个人
I need somebody killed
我听说你手底下的有最好的杀手
and I heard that you employ the best.
没错  我知道你
Oh, yes, I know you.
我们杰出市长的妹妹
Our illustrious Mayor's sister.
或者该说是前市长
Or should I say "Ex-Mayor"?
听道上说  你也是个神枪手啊
Word is, you're quite the deadeye yourself.
为什么还来找我们
Why come to us?
出了点事故  失了准头
Had an accident. My aim is off.
是公事还是私仇
Is this business, personal...?
跟你有关系吗
What's it matter to you?
私仇要加价
Personal costs extra.
总会出现意外情况
There's always complications.
是公事
It's business.
一个警察
A cop.
看起来是私仇啊
Seems personal to me.
反正警察也要加价
Anyhow, cops also cost extra.
行
Fine.
我要今天就办成
I want it done today.
我能得到什么保证
What kind of guarantee do I get?
我接下活儿  就能办成  就这样
I accept the job, the job gets done. Period.
我深信非常手段的魅力
You see, I believe in the beauty of extreme measures.
这个幸运儿是谁
So who's the lucky fellow?
基恩小姐还没恢复意识
Ms. Kean has yet to regain consciousness.
受了这么重的伤
With this kind of trauma,
我们也不知道她什么时候能醒来
we have no idea when she might wake up.
要是还能醒来的话
If ever.
但阿卡姆的医疗部设备齐全
But the medical wing at Arkham is fully equipped
可以应付她的状况
to handle her condition.
你会送她转移吗
Will you be riding over with her?
不会
No.
起床了  瞌睡虫
Hello, sleepyhead.
我在哪里
Where am I?
剧烈运动会使心跳加速
Rapid movement and elevated heart rate
不利于康复过程
are counterproductive to the healing process.
不  不  不要杀我
No! No! Don't kill me!
我先道个歉
Apologies in advance.
好好睡吧  我有羽毛的朋友
Rest up, my feathered friend.
今晚可很重要呢
We have a big night ahead of us.
哥谭
第二季  第九集
在找这个吗
Looking for this?
谢谢
Thank you.
我没醒  你就走了
You left before I woke up.
是啊  我睡不着
I know. Couldn't sleep.
我打呼噜了吗
Was I snoring?
-没有  -你确定吗
- No. - Are you sure?
我没鼾声如雷  让你震耳欲聋吗
My big, loud, rumbling, barnyard snore?
有人向我抱怨过  邻居啊
I've heard complaints-- neighbors,
飞机啊
airplanes...
你不打呼噜
You don't snore.
是这样  我很高兴盖勒文被抓起来了
Look, I'm glad Galavan's been arrested,
但他应该为自己的罪行付出代价
but he should pay for everything he's done.
我和巴恩斯约好在盖勒文的顶层公寓见面
I'm on my way to meet Barnes at Galavan's penthouse.
希望能找到证据
Hopefully, we can find some evidence
支持奥布雷·詹姆斯的证词
to corroborate Aubrey James' testimony.
我接到电话
I got a call.
他们要将芭芭拉转到阿卡姆疯人院
They're transferring Barbara to Arkham.
我知道  我去过哥谭总院
I know. I stopped by Gotham General.
你去看她了吗
You went to see her?
她是能让盖勒文被定罪的证人
She's a witness against Galavan.
我想去看看她的情况
I wanted to check on her condition.
她的情况就是昏迷不醒
Her condition is she's in a coma.
我们还没谈过
We never talked about what happened
你跟芭芭拉在审讯室里发生的事
with you and Barbara in that interrogation room.
我知道  今晚行吗
I know. Tonight?
行  今晚
Sure, tonight.
现在说也行
Or right now.
小莱  我是因为盖勒文案才去看她的
Lee, I went over to see her as a part of the case against Galavan,
没别的
that is it.
我不是吃醋
This isn't jealousy.
那个女人...
That woman is...
怎么形容呢
How do I put this?
她是个魔鬼
She's the devil.
她就是  她是恶魔
No, she is. She's the devil.
小莱
Lee...
你觉得我希望事情发展成这样吗
you think I wanted things to go the way they did?
我不得不配合她
I had to play her game.
我懂
I know.
不说芭芭拉了
Uh, forget about Barbara.
大部分人会抵抗自己的阴暗面
Most people fight their dark side.
而你最近却努力向黑暗屈服
Lately, you find ways to give in to it.
这是个问题
That's a problem.
对你  对我们都是问题
For you and for us.
我懂
I know.
我明白你的意思
I hear you.
我们能不现在谈这些吗
Can we please just not talk about this right now?
我要去见巴恩斯  快迟到了
I'm late to meet Barnes.
我不会有事
I'll be fine.
我都不确定你是不是还会想见我
I wasn't sure you'd ever want to see me again.
你联系我时...
When you called...
你不相信他们所说关于我叔叔的话
You don't believe what they're saying about my uncle...
对吧
do you?
不
No.
当然不信
Of course not.
茜尔薇  我找你来是想请你帮忙
Silver, I asked you here because I need your help.
什么都行
Anything.
他被捕前  曾向我提出个提议
Before he was arrested, your uncle made me an offer.
-我想  -好了  布鲁斯少爷  快起来
- I want... - Right, Master Bruce! On your feet.
我从五金店买了几把很棒的耙子
Bought us a lovely couple of rakes from the ironmonger's.
我建议我们出去
I suggest we get outside and get...
你好  圣克劳德小姐
Hello, Ms. St. Cloud.
没想到你会在这里
Did not expect to see you here.
-你好  阿尔弗雷德  -外面大路上
- Hello, Alfred. - That must have been your car I saw,
那辆没熄火的车肯定是你的吧
idling on the main road.
鉴于最近发生的事
Now, in light of recent events,
我建议你最好还是上车离开
I suggest you get in it and you leave.
马上
Immediately.
是我请她来的  我要她留下
I invited her, and I want her to stay.
我命令她离开
And I'm ordering her to leave.
这是我家  命令该由我下
And it's my house, and I give the orders.
是吗
Oh, is that so?
没关系的
It's okay.
我不想给你们添麻烦
I don't want to cause any trouble.
真聪明
Smart girl.
赶紧走吧
Off you pop.
我住凯恩酒店
I'm at the Kane Hotel.
你无权这么做
You had no right to do that.
我绝对有权这么做
I had every right.
你怎么想的啊  把她找来
What were you thinking, asking her up here?
等等  你是
Oh, wait, you...
想从她那儿问出点什么
think she was gonna tell you something.
如果盖勒文那信封里真有杀害我父母
If Galavan really has the name of my parents' killer
真凶的名字  那就值得一试
in that envelope, it's worth a shot.
我的想法是那信封里什么也没有
Well, my guess is there was absolutely nothing in that envelope.
那只是骗你转让公司的诡计而已
It was just a ruse to get you to sign away the company.
盖勒文很聪明
Galavan is smart.
他绝不会没有筹码就随便提出
He wouldn't enter a multibillion-dollar offer
上百万的交易
without his end of the bargain.
他肯定知道真凶的名字
He has the name.
而你觉得那只小狐狸精
And you think that little minx
会告诉你吗
is gonna tell you something, do you?
我们是朋友
We're friends.
不  你们不是
No, you're not.
要从那样的女孩口中套取信息
Getting information out of a girl like that
需要一定程度的骗术
requires a level of deception
目前你还没那个本事  布鲁斯少爷
that you do not yet possess, Master Bruce.
这太危险了
It is too dangerous.
这个险值得冒
It's worth the risk.
不
No.
你不能再和圣克劳德小姐见面了
You will not see Ms. St. Cloud again
也不能去追查盖勒文疯狂的说法
or pursue Galavan's wild claims.
你没有权利替我做出那个决定
You have no right to make that decision for me.
总得有人做啊
Well, someone has to.
假如你逼我像看犯人一样看着你...
If you force me to be your jailer...
那我别无选择
then that is who I will be.
抱歉  谢了
Excuse me. Thank you.
按下56  麻烦了
Press 56, please?
你住在这里吗
You live here?
不是
No.
我也不是
Me neither.
有位女士的小钢琴走音了  所以...
Lady's baby grand is flat, so...
我不介意上门维修  我喜欢我的工作
I don't mind making house calls. I like my work.
你喜欢你的工作吗
You like your work?
嗯  喜欢
Yeah. I do.
那我们挺幸运的
I guess we're lucky.
吃糖吗
Caramel?
不用了  谢谢
No, I'm good.
你的损失  这糖可好吃了
You're missing out; they're good.
戈登怎么还不来
Where the hell is Gordon?
那是谁
Who is that?
不知道
No idea.
但他刚刚试图杀我
But he just tried to kill me.
他说了为什么吗
He tell you why?
反正不是临时起意
Wasn't random.
钢琴线
Piano wire.
这家伙是职业杀手
Guy's a pro.
不  等等  等等
No, wait, wait.
觉得自己运气好吗  奈德
You feeling lucky, Ned?
你行的
You got this!
听好了
Listen up.
谁想去除掉一个哥谭警察
Who wants a shot at eighty-sixing one of Gotham's finest?
有附带伤害也无所谓
I'm waiving any collateral fines.
你们想怎么做都行
Just do what you have to do,
但是吉姆·戈登今晚必须...死
but Jim Gordon doesn't see the sun... rise.
你给我下药
You drugged me.
那是为了你自己好  企鹅先生
That was for your own benefit, Mr. Penguin.
你受了重伤
You have extensive injuries.
我认识你
I know you.
爱德
Ed.
尼格玛
Nygma.
我们之前见过一次  在哥谭市警局
We met once before, at the GCPD.
你不是警察
You're not a cop.
不不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
不  我是鉴证科的
No, I'm in forensics.
你相信命运吗
Do you believe in fate?
我的衣服哪去了
Where are my clothes?
我给扔掉了  有异味
Oh, I threw them away. They smelled.
不  天呐
Oh, no. Oh, my.
先生  恐怕你不能走
Uh, I'm afraid, sir, that you can't leave.
再给我打一次镇静剂  我发誓我...
You sedate me again, and I swear, I will...
先生
Sir!
你是个通缉犯
You are a wanted man.
你可以逃跑试试看
You can try and run,
但是照你的状况  最多只能跑出三个街区
but with your condition, you'll get about three blocks.
恐怕康复之前  你都得待在这儿
I'm afraid that you're stuck here until you recover.
来喝吧
Now, drink up.
这只是水
It's just water.
长时间在户外活动之后  脱水是正常现象
Dehydration is common after prolonged outdoor exposure.
你想怎样
What do you want from me?
还记得我提到了命运吗
Remember I had mentioned fate?
最近我在经历一些变化
Recently, I've been going through a sort of change.
什么样的变化  你问
"What kind of change?" You ask.
我没问
I didn't.
我开始杀人了
I've started murdering people.
说出来真是令人兴奋
That is thrilling to say out loud.
杀了多少人
How many people?
总共三个
Three in total.
其中两个我根本不在乎
Two of them I didn't really care for.
但另一个是我女朋友柯林格小姐
But one was my girlfriend, Ms. Kringle.
她是我一生的挚爱
She was the love of my life.
如果你打算杀了我
If you're planning on killing me,
就赶紧动手吧
could you get on with it?
到了现在  这也算解脱了
At this point, it would come as a welcome relief.
老天  不不不
Oh, heavens. No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
我对你绝无恶意
I have no ill intentions toward you.
那你有什么意图
Then what are your intentions?
我需要你的建议
I need advice,
企鹅先生
Mr. Penguin.
这三次杀人
These murders...
改变了我
changed me.
就像蝴蝶
And like the butterfly,
我已经意识到我不可能再变回毛毛虫
I've come to realize that I cannot be a caterpillar once again.
而你是这座城市最臭名昭著的杀人犯之一
And you're one of the city's most notorious killers.
我带你来这儿  部分原因
I brought you here, in part,
是希望你可以在这条新路上指引我
because I was hoping you could guide me on this new path.
朋友
Listen, friend...
我叫爱德
Ed.
随便吧
Whatever.
我的帝国已经毁了
My empire is in ruins.
我是个没有朋友的通缉犯
I'm a wanted man with no friends.
而我母亲
And my mother...
那个我发誓要保护的人死了
the one person I swore to protect is dead
就因为我的软弱
because of my weakness.
相信我  这条道路带给你的
Believe me when I tell you that this path you're on
只有毁灭和痛苦
leads to nothing but destruction and pain.
所以
So...
不管我是不是通缉犯
wanted or not...
我要走了
I'm leaving.
天啊
Oh, my.
快醒醒吧
Rise and shine.
不管了
Hell with this.
谁派你来的
Who sent you? Huh?
是谁派你来的
Who sent you?!
你母亲
Your mother.
我就希望你这么说呢
That's what I was hoping you would say.
不  不要
No! Don't!
快说
Talk!
戈登警探  住手
Detective Gordon, stand down!
马上住手
Stand down right now!
帕克斯  看住犯人
Parks, watch the perp.
科特兹  把窗户关上
Cortez, you shut the window.
你过来
Come over here!
你明明知道我不容许这种行为
You know damn well I don't tolerate that type of behavior,
却还在我眼皮底下明知故犯
and yet you pull that crap right in front of me?
抱歉  长官
I'm sorry, sir.
你是不是疯了  戈登
Are you losing it, Gordon?
你的脑子被教堂发生的事情搅乱了吗
Has that church incident messed with your mind?
没有  长官
No, sir.
如果我没记错的话
'Cause if I remember correctly,
正是因为你不服从我的命令
you disobeying my orders
才害你被绑去了那里
is what landed you there in the first place.
我命令你掉转车头
I ordered you to turn that car around,
而你却置之不理并直接中了埋伏
and you ignored me and drove straight into an ambush.
最终抓住了盖勒文
And ended the day putting Galavan behind bars.
我们必须采取非常手段
We need to push the boundaries.
警监
Captain!
我的雇主有严格规矩
My employer has a strict protocol.
如果第一个人没有成功
If the first guy doesn't succeed,
就继续派人来直到任务完成
keep sending men till the job is done.
你们没人能活着离开这里
None of you is making it out of here alive.
到这儿后  行动要小心
When you get here, move carefully.
我们不知道要对付多少罪犯
We don't know how many active skells we're dealing with.
好的
All right.
两支小队正在赶来
Two units on the way here.
我们要坚守到他们到来
We just have to hold out till they get here.
科特兹  把灯关掉
Hey, Cortez, kill the lights.
长官  我是鉴证科的
Sir, I'm forensics.
我没有枪
I don't have a gun.
找个东西当武器
Grab something you can use as a weapon,
然后尽可能躲在我们后面  好吗
and stay behind us as best you can, all right?
帕克斯  在那张桌子后面隐蔽
Parks, take cover behind the desk.
回忆你的训练
Remember your training.
瞄准中央大面积区域
Aim for center mass.
是  中央大面积区
Right. Center mass.
确认敌人被干掉之前不要停火
And don't stop firing until you're sure.
还有  帕克斯
And, Parks...
是  长官
Yes, sir?
深呼吸
Breathe.
救我
Help me!
放下刀子
Drop the knife!
我要离开了
I'm leaving.
别做梦了
Not gonna happen.
要是阻止我
Try to stop me.
我就割下她漂亮的小脑袋
I'll lop off her pretty little head.
知道我喜欢你眼镜的哪一点吗
You know what I like about those glasses?
看起来像靶心
They look like bull's-eyes.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
I am.
好了
Okay!
咱们不能留下等第二波了
We're not gonna hang around for round two.
拿上证物
Everybody load up,
咱们赶紧离开这里
and let's get the hell out of here.
我不走
I'm not leaving.
这不是请求
That wasn't a request.
这依然是最可能找到
This place is still our best bet
能给盖勒文定罪的证据的地方
for evidence against Galavan.
我们走了  他们就会摧毁证据
We leave, they'll destroy it.
你这就是在没事找事
Now you're just looking for a fight.
帕克斯  去确认楼梯安全
Parks, make sure the staircase is clear.
现在死了一个平民
I've got a civilian who's dead
还有一个新兵被吓得半死
and a rookie who's scared half out of her mind.
你觉得我们凭这几把手枪
You think we're gonna survive the next attack
能挺过下一波攻击吗
with just a few handguns?
咱们得赶紧离开这里
We have to get out of here.
等下
Wait.
僧侣的袍子
A monk's cassock?
这是干什么的
What the hell is this about?
我不知道
I don't know,
但是咱们得赶快离开这里
but we have to get out of here.
走吧
Let's go!
警监
Captain...
Captain!
这可能就是我们要找的东西
This could be exactly what we're looking for.
刀
Knife!
警监
Captain!
警监  你没事吧
Captain! You okay?
只是擦伤而已
It's just a scratch.
咱们快走吧
Let's get out of here.
不行  刀划破了动脉
No, no. The knife punctured an artery.
你乱动  伤口可能会撕裂
You move, it could tear.
你把自己当医生呢  我可以动
What are you, a doctor now? I can move.
你一站起来
You stand up,
几分钟内就会失血过多而死
you'll bleed out in a matter of minutes.
那是谁
Who is that?
这位是莱纳德先生
This is Mr. Leonard.
昨晚你说梦话
You were talking in your sleep last night
说盖勒文杀了你母亲
about Galavan killing your mother.
是吗
I was?
是的
Yes.
莱纳德先生...
Mr. Leonard...
是盖勒文的手下
...works for Galavan.
当然是他被捕之前的事了
Well, before he was arrested, of course.
被捕
Arrested?
戈登警探以绑架詹姆斯市长为由
Detective Gordon arrested Galavan
逮捕了盖勒文
for kidnapping Mayor James.
他进了黑门监狱
He's in Blackgate!
我以为你会高兴
Oh, I thought you'd be pleased.
无所谓了
It doesn't matter anymore.
他怎么会在这儿
Why is he here?
是给你的礼物
He was a gift for you.
我该拿莱纳德怎么办
And what exactly am I supposed to do with a Leonard?
杀了他
Kill him.
我想着为你母亲的死报复一下
I thought it might be nice to get some retribution
对你会比较好
for your mother's death.
也许能让你高兴点
That it might cheer you up a little.
不是吗
No?
我不干了
I'm done.
我需要休息
I need some rest.
然后我要永远离开哥谭
And then I'm leaving Gotham forever.
我真以为他会喜欢你
I really thought he would like you.
现在怎么办
What to do now?
求你了  求你了
Please! Please!
别吃我的...
Not my...!
能尝到受害者的恐惧的滋味
Why just smell the fear on your victim
为什么只用鼻子闻呢  对吧
when you can taste it, right?
救我
Help me!
救命  救命
Help! Help!
喂
Hola.
好啊  爱德华多
Hola, Eduardo.
好久没联系
Long time.
是啊
Yes.
稍等片刻
Just a moment, please.
救命  救命
Help! Help!
你在执行任务吗
Are you on a job?
如果很享受  就不叫任务
It's not a job if you love what you do.
好吧
Oh, fair enough.
是这样  我这儿需要你帮忙
Listen, um, I'm in a bit of a pinch over here.
我以为我的会员资格被取消了
I thought my membership was revoked.
过去的事了  亲爱的
Bygones, darling.
得饶人处且饶人嘛
Live and let live.
你不就喜欢吃人嘛
So you eat people.
我有什么权利说三道四呢
Who am I to judge?
目标是一位戈登警探
The target is a Detective Gordon.
我不会亏待你的
I'll make it worth your while.
把地址发给我
Send me the address.
敢死队都比你温柔
Death squads have softer touches than you.
至少盖勒文都喝好酒
At least Galavan goes top shelf.
救护人员应该就来了
The EMTs should be on their way.
没错
Yeah, sure.
他们会和支援前后脚赶到
They'll be here about the same time as our backup.
你要不要说说自己到底怎么了
So you want to tell me what the hell's going on with you?
那天在教堂
In the church that day,
芭芭拉说我心中潜藏着一个恶魔
Barbara accused me of having a monster inside me.
然后呢
And?
小莱似乎也赞同
Lee seems to agree.
她认为我已经准备好并愿意向恶魔屈服
She thinks I'm ready and willing to give in to it.
你怎么想
What do you think?
有那么一瞬间
There was a moment.
当我拿猎枪对着芭芭拉时
When I had the shotgun on Barbara.
她嘲弄我  想诱我开枪
She was taunting me to pull the trigger.
如果盖勒文的人没有冲进来...
If Galavan's people hadn't busted in...
不好说会怎么样
I don't know.
但他们确实冲进来了
But they did bust in.
我差点就要越线了
I nearly crossed the line.
"界线"
"The line."
我和你说说界线吧
Let me tell you something about the line.
我第三次派驻时  我们驻扎在沙漠
My third tour, we were stationed in the desert.
我们抓捕了三个叛乱分子  却遭遇了沙尘暴
We captured three insurgents, when this sandstorm kicks up.
能见度为零
Zero visibility.
接着我们遭遇了火力  受到袭击
Then we start taking fire. We're getting lit up.
突然我只身一人了
Suddenly, I'm alone.
我遇上了其中一个囚犯
I come across one of our prisoners.
是个孩子
He's a kid.
他的手被绑起来了
His hands are zip-tied.
但他不顾一切
But he figures, what the hell,
打算利用沙尘暴逃跑
he's gonna use the sandstorm to try to escape.
于是我朝他扑去
So I jump him.
我用我的枪塞进了他的嘴
And I take my gun and I jam it in his mouth.
我以为只是威胁他
I figured it was just a threat.
让他知道厉害
Show him who's boss, you know?
紧接着...
Next thing I know...
我就扣动了扳机
I just pulled the trigger.
打爆了他的头
Blew his head off.
多年来那个孩子每晚都会把我惊醒
That kid woke me up every night for years.
直到我放下了心结
Until I made my peace with him.
我渐渐明白自己只是个普通人
See, I come to find out I'm just a man.
在一定场合下
And at the right moment,
一个人可能做出任何事
a man might do anything.
任何人都是如此
Any man.
根本没有界线
There is no line.
只有法律
There's just the law.
这才是我们和那些畜生的区分
That's what separates us from the animals.
根本没有界线
There is no line.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred?
我考虑了你的话
I thought about what you said.
你是对的
And you're right.
自己去追查盖勒文太危险了
Pursuing Galavan on my own is too risky.
可不是呢
Well, you don't say.
最好的办法是早上打给戈登警探
Best course of action is call Detective Gordon in the morning.
请求他帮忙
Enlist his help.
终于想通了
At last, some sense.
你要就寝了吗  少爷
You're thinking of retiring, are you, sir?
是的  是很累了
Yeah, yeah. Very tired.
嗯  那您上床前要给您拿点什么吃吗
Right, can I get you anything to eat before you go to bed?
不用
No.
不用了  谢谢  阿尔弗雷德
No, thank you, Alfred.
那祝您好梦  对了  布鲁斯少爷
Right, well, sleep well. Oh, and, uh, Master Bruce?
我叫那辆停在街尾的车走了
I sent that car off that's parked at the end of the lane.
就是那辆出租车
You know, the taxi.
别担心  我给了他不少小费
Don't worry, I gave him a right good tip.
毕竟人家都一路开到这儿来了
I mean, after all, he did drive all the way up here, didn't he?
我没叫出租车啊
I didn't call a taxi.
你真是...
You really are the most...
最不会撒谎的孩子了  布鲁斯少爷
terrible liar, aren't you, Master Bruce?
我不会放弃的  阿尔弗雷德
I will not stop pursuing this, Alfred.
我永远不会放弃的
I'm never going to give up.
我也不会
And nor will I.
晚安  少爷
Good night, sir.
*火已熄灭*
*The fire has gone out*
*雪湿透衣衫*
*Wet snow from above*
*没什么能比妈妈的爱*
*But nothing will warm me more*
*更让我感到温暖*
*Than my, my mother's love*
*我又点亮一支蜡烛*
*I light another candle*
*想擦干我脸上的泪水*
*To dry the tears from my face...*
你为什么要弹这首歌
Why are you playing this song?
我可以让你眼眶湿润
I can bring tears to your eyes
我可以复活死者
and resurrect the dead.
形成只需顷刻  却能绵延终生
I form in an instant and last a lifetime.
我是什么
What am I?
记忆
A memory.
那又如何
So what?
你在被子下面哼这首歌来着
You were humming this under your covers.
我猜这一定对你有什么意义
I figure it has meaning for you.
我小时候  每一晚
Every night when I was young,
我母亲都给我唱那首歌
my mother would sing that song to me
哄我入睡
when I was going to bed.
她每次都会对我说
And every time, she would tell me...
"奥斯瓦尔德
"Oswald...
别听其他孩子瞎说
"...don't listen to the other children.
你又帅  又聪明
"You're handsome and clever.
总有一日  你会成为伟大的人"
And some day, you will be a great man."
她每次都那么说
She said that every time.
我现在只有这个了
That's all I have left now.
记忆
Memories.
他们就像刺在我心里的匕首
And they're like daggers in my heart.
不会永远如此
Not forever.
这是柯林格小姐的
These were Ms. Kringle's.
是我对她唯一的念想
It's all I have left to remember her by.
但我现在看着它  不再觉得悲哀了
But when I look at these, I don't feel sadness anymore.
我觉得感激  知道为什么吗
I feel gratitude. And do you know why?
不  我也不在乎
No. And I don't care.
这段小小造访结束了
This little visit is over.
我就跟你
I will just simply bid you
道别了
adieu.
企鹅先生
Mr. Penguin.
对有些男人来说  爱是力量的源泉
For some men, love is a source of strength.
但对你我来说  那永远只是
But for you and I, it will always be
我们的致命软肋
our most crippling weakness.
让开  爱德
Move aside, Ed!
没用羁绊  对我们更好
We are better off unencumbered.
你说什么
What did you say?
你自己也这么说
You said it yourself.
你母亲的死  是因为你的软弱
Your mother is dead because of your weakness.
但你需要明白  你的软弱之处
But what you need to realize is that your weakness
就是她
was her.
我母亲是个圣人
My mother was a saint!
她是唯一真心关心过我的人
The only person who truly cared about me,
现在她死了
and now she's gone!
我一无所有了
And I have nothing left!
一个人没有任何所爱
A man with nothing that he loves...
就不会被人抓到把柄
...is a man who cannot be bargained.
不会被背叛
A man that cannot be betrayed.
不需要对任何人负责
A man who answers to no one...
只听自己的
but himself.
我眼前  就是这样一个人
And that is the man that I see before me.
自由的人
A free man.
急救人员来了吗
Are the EMTs with you?
巴恩斯警监需要立刻救助
Captain Barnes needs immediate attention.
救护车还在路上
Ambulance is still inbound.
我们会封锁周边  等等...
We'll secure the perimeter... Wait, wait, hold on!
你身后
Behind you!
警官
Officer?
Officer?!
你好
Hola.
戈登警探吧
Detective Gordon, I presume?
你是谁
Who is this?
我是爱德华多·弗拉明戈
This is Eduardo Flamingo.
我应该听过你的大名吗
Is that name supposed to mean something to me?
你现在不知道
Not yet.
但你会知道我的厉害的
But it will.
我马上就上楼去
I'll be upstairs in a few minutes.
我要先吃掉你的朋友
I'm going to feast on your friends first.
然后留你做甜点
Save you for dessert.
你敢跑
You try to run,
我一定会找到你
I will find you.
我不会跑的
I won't.
事实上  我这就下去
In fact, I'm coming down.
下面怎么回事
What the hell is going on down there?
又来了一个杀手
We've got another hit man.
他刚杀了我们的支援
He's just taken out all of our backup.
我要下去了结此事
I'm going down to end this.
你...他刚杀了四个警察
You... He just killed four cops!
你不能自己去
You're not going anywhere on your own.
他说得对  我跟你一起去
He's right. I'm coming with you.
不  你留下
No, you're staying here.
你得确保他不会大出血死亡
You need to make sure he doesn't bleed out.
我刚说了  你不能自己下去
I just said you're not going down there solo.
我们让他们上来
We'll make them come to us.
我们坐在这里  就是瓮中之鳖
We stay here, we're sitting ducks.
他要的是我  头儿
He's after me, boss.
去吧
Go.
小莱
亲爱的
Oh, baby.
你真让我失望
You disappoint me.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
我建议你好好行使这个权利
I suggest you use it.
我会去办好手续把他关起来
I'll make sure he gets processed and put in lockup.
多谢
Thanks.
帕克斯
And, Parks...
你今天干得很棒
you did good today.
*因为我妈妈照顾我*
*For my mother looks over me.*
再来
And again!
*火已熄灭*
*The fire has gone out*
*雪湿透衣衫*
*Wet snow from above*
*没什么能比妈妈的爱*
*But nothing will warm me more*
*更让我感到温暖*
*Than my, my mother's love.*
你之前绑起来的那家伙呢
What happened to that gentleman you had tied up earlier?
盖勒文的走狗吗
Galavan's lackey?
怎么了
Why do you ask?
我母亲总说
My mother always said
没有节目助兴  派对不算尽兴
a party is not a party without entertainment.
想偷溜出去见你女朋友吗
Sneaking out to see your girlfriend, huh?
塞琳娜  你来做什么
Selina, what are you doing here?
避免你犯下大错
Saving your ass from making a big mistake.
茜尔薇不是好人  布鲁斯
Silver is bad news, Bruce.
这话你说过
You've said that before.
这次  我有证据
This time, I have proof.
你想看吗
You interested?
你要蹲很久的监狱了  弗拉明戈先生
You're going away for a long time, Mr. Flamingo.
起来
Get up!
我叫你起来
I said get up!
小莱
Lee...
别动
Hold still.
谢谢
Thank you.
我今晚差点做了过界的事
I almost crossed the line tonight.
可不是
No kidding.
真不像你
How out of character.
我有点吓到了
Scared me a little.
我早就吓到了
Welcome to my world.
你为什么跟我在一起
Why the hell are you with me?
我也不知道
Beats me.
跟我说实话
Just tell me the truth.
永远跟我说实话
Always.
我保证
I promise.
詹姆斯·戈登警探电话
Detective James Gordon's phone.
我是小莱·汤普金斯
This is Lee Thompkins speaking.
你好  阿尔瓦雷斯
Hi, Alvarez.
我会转告他的
I'll tell him.
爱德华多·弗拉明戈杀了帕克斯警官
Eduardo Flamingo killed Officer Parks
然后才被制服关起来
before they could get him into lockup.
杀手
Hit men?
你派杀手去对付吉姆·戈登
You sent hit men after Jim Gordon,
我明确告诉你不许妄动
after I expressly told you to do nothing
除非我下命令
until I gave you orders?
不许妄动
Nothing.
不是为了芭芭拉吧
Tell me this isn't about Barbara.
他伤害了她
He hurt her.
你居然让那种女人搅乱你的心绪  我真失望
I'm disappointed that you let a woman like that get in your head.
如果你不好受
If you're feeling upset,
就去找个图书管理员折磨折磨
find yourself a nice librarian to torture.
总能让你开心
That always cheers you up.
现在已经万事俱备了
Everything is ready.
兄弟们即将到来
The brothers' arrival is imminent.
布鲁斯·韦恩必死无疑
Bruce Wayne will die,
他的公司  和这座城市  都将归我
and his company and this city will be mine.
归我们
Ours.
我们为之努力了那么久的一切
Everything that we have worked for for so long
都将成为我们的
will be ours.
你再敢拿这事冒险  尽管我会伤心欲绝
Endanger that prize again, and though it breaks my heart,
我还是会割了你的喉咙
I will cut your throat.
欢迎  兄弟们
Welcome, brothers.
欢迎
Welcome.
码头已经关闭了
Docks are closed.
请出示身份证明
I need to see some I.D.
等等
Wait...
不要
No!